# Siddharth Hathi

git: sidHathi

email: sid.24@dartmouth.edu

c phone: (425) 835-6125

linkedin: www.linkedin.com/in/sidhathi/

web: www.sidhathi.com

### **Summary**

I am a versatile engineer with experience in software development as well as UI/UX design. I played a key role in a technology startup contributing to marketing, design, engineering and project management. I work well within teams and I am extremely passionate about building awesome new technology. Currently enrolled at Dartmouth College studying Computer Science and Engineering

# **Education**

### **Dartmouth College '24**

Studying CS and Engineering, 3.72 GPA (Provisional)

#### Lakeside School '20

1570 SAT, 3.94 GPA

### **Stanford Machine Learning (Coursera)**

**Grade: 100%** 

## **Skills and Abilities**

- JavaScript
- React.js
- Swift
- HTML5/CSS
- PHP
- 0
- Java
- bash/shell
- c#
- Python
- Matlab
- Unity
- MySQL

- Firebase
- Web SEO
- Basic machine learning
- UI/UX Design
- Graphic design
- CAD Modeling
- Social media marketing
- VR/AR Developement
- Adobe Illustrator
- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe Xd
- Videography
- Fluent in Spanish

# **Employment History**

### Research Assistant

# Relatavistic Electron Atmospheric Loss (2021-Present)

 Created online satellite visualization tool using React.js that displayed a live 3D model of an orbiting satellite that updated in real time.

### **Chief Design Officer**

### **Ghost Pacer (2019-2021)**

Ghost Pacer builds AR training glasses for runners. They develop the complete system including firmware, optics, and the associated mobile app. Launched on Kickstarter Aug 2020.

- Designed Kickstarter campaign that generated \$150 thousand in 30 days
- Created much of iOS mobile app including UI/UX, Strava API integration, map rendering, data architecture, analytics, bluetooth integration, and Firebase
- Designed and developed product and corporate websites
- Managed design for marketing and social media campaigns
- Part of leadership team where I contributed to strategy and management decisions

### **Assistant Project Leader**

### **Dartmouth Humanitarian Engineering (2021-Present)**

- Co-lead team of 15 Dartmouth students working on creating a cheap, multi-terrain wheelchair for use in urban environments
- Member of Executive board, where my responsibilities include managing the club's finances and securing project funding

### **Research Intern**

### Lakeside Summer Research Institute (2016)

 Adapted computer model of snowfall for avalanche forecasting and climate change research. Presented at UW conference.

# **Projects**

- Built website for students in my high school that allows them to rate and review their classes
- Built SwiftUI app to connect restaurants to foodbanks
- Building JavaScript messaging app to enable more streamlined messaging and scheduling
- Built lossless text compressor using Huffman encoding
- Built server/socket based multi-user image editor (Java)
- Used machine learning to conduct analysis on stock market data using Python and web scraping
- Built iOS game using SpriteKit and custom physics that was distributed within my high school
- Built VR game that was distributed in my high school
- Built 2D rocket simulator in Unity for high school physics
- Volunteered for a month in Colombia where I did manual labor and videography in rural village
- Won 3rd place in Washington state **photography** competition